<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on My Data Science Portfolio</title>
    <link>https://szystem.github.io/main/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on My Data Science Portfolio</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 22 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://szystem.github.io/main/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>SVM classifier from scratch</title>
      <link>https://szystem.github.io/main/post/2022-02-22-svmc/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://szystem.github.io/main/post/2022-02-22-svmc/</guid>
      <description>As a part of a bigger project, I wrote Support Vector Machine Classifier. It supports multiclass clasification, linear and radial kernels, and both hard and soft margins.
Check out:
 The project&amp;rsquo;s Jupyter Notebook  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Face recognition techniques comparison</title>
      <link>https://szystem.github.io/main/post/2022-02-08-face-recognition/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://szystem.github.io/main/post/2022-02-08-face-recognition/</guid>
      <description>For two weeks my two colleagues and I have been working on a group project, whose goal is to compare the performance of different algorithms in face recognition. We are focused on SVMs with different kernels and convnets. One more goal is to use data augmentation and transfer learning methods to train a network even on a very small data set. Our final goal is to check network vulnerability by incorporating the adversarial machine learning techniques.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Master&#39;s Project Update</title>
      <link>https://szystem.github.io/main/post/2022-01-06-master1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://szystem.github.io/main/post/2022-01-06-master1/</guid>
      <description>My biggest project this year is going to be my Master&amp;rsquo;s Project. In it I extend the possibilities of the EM algorithm to cluster Dirichlet distributed data evolving in time. Project consists of a number of steps:
 Programming a simple EM algorithm for normally distrubuted data Adjusting the algorithm for the dirichlet distribution Developing the model suitable for a data consisting of observations evolving in time Testing the algorithm on a synthetic data set Cleaning and preparing a real-life data set - marital statuses in countries in different group ages Applying the algorithm for the real data  The .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project Rook Endings</title>
      <link>https://szystem.github.io/main/post/2022-01-05-project-chessrookendings/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://szystem.github.io/main/post/2022-01-05-project-chessrookendings/</guid>
      <description>Another project I have made concerns my childhood hobby: the game of chess. This famous data set contains coordinates of three pieces on a chessboard: white king, white rook and black king and optimal depth-of-win for White in 0 to 16 moves, otherwise drawn, assuming that Black moves first. Check out:
 The project&amp;rsquo;s website The project&amp;rsquo;s repository  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project Stone Flakes</title>
      <link>https://szystem.github.io/main/post/2022-01-05-project-stoneflakes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://szystem.github.io/main/post/2022-01-05-project-stoneflakes/</guid>
      <description>I have uploaded on github my first data science project, called Stone Flakes. It concerns the earliest history of mankind, investigating stone flakes, the waste product of the tools&#39; crafting process. The main question related to the data set is: &amp;ldquo;Does the data reflect the technological progress during several hundred thousand years?” Check out:
 The project&amp;rsquo;s website The project&amp;rsquo;s repository  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First post!</title>
      <link>https://szystem.github.io/main/post/2022-01-04-first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://szystem.github.io/main/post/2022-01-04-first-post/</guid>
      <description>Hello! I am launching this website as a central point of my professional online presence. Here you can see my projects and other achievements.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
